Welcome back.
So in the previous tutorial, we successfully built the services.
Okay, so in this section we will see whether our service is really running or not.
So it all sounds simple successfully, but now let's see whether it's actually runs or not.
Okay, so I'm just a first time emulator, ADB Shell, I'm getting in Verity, Michelle and I'm listing
the services which are actually running now.
Let it come.
So I have got all the services which is actually currently running.
So we have 169 services actually.
So so ourselves is not running at the moment.
Okay.
So we need to understand why.
Let's just do one thing.
So we will first see the logcat, whether it's actually what happened, actually why it didn't triggered.
So what I'm going to do is I will just be low.
Got to.
No.
God, no.
This is my look at file, which is created just now.
Okay, so if I go down and search Android, it is not a good idea to use the name as always.
So his name as Android as you can use a different name so that it's easy to go through the locate because
the logcat there will be hundreds of places where you have the Android editor nowadays, so it will
be hard for you to search.
So I would suggest you to just change, replace the android with some other name and then use the scripts.
So what happened now is the permission is denied.
So you can see here is Linux, ABC denied add for service.
So this is our service name.
And this is the IED.
And here you have some information.
Okay.
So here you're going to see that our service this is a service name service is actually blocked.
Android service failed.
Okay.
So we know now that it has failed.
And the reason for that is actually Linux.
Okay.
So we can see here that it has failed due to SELinux policies.
Okay, so what exactly say SELinux policy?
So itself is another big topic, actually, we need to understand before we build any Android device.
Okay.
So for now, just keep in mind it is actually a set of policies.
So basically all objects in Android has a label in it and each label has some permissions.
And that is done through a C policies.
So basically when we create a service, we need to explicitly say that this service has the right to
get added to the to the process or whatever.
So there is different, different domains and each label should have different, different access to
the domains.
Okay.
So that enhances the security of Android.
So for now, just keep that in mind.
And okay, so there is an alternate do as well.
So you can actually disable assailant's policies.
Like if there is two modes, there is permissive mode and then enforcement mode.
So again, now by default, Android is in enforcement mode.
So you can change it diplomacy mode.
But we are not going to do that now.
What we do is we just try to fix this problem.
Okay.
So in order to fix this, what you need to do is you just need to.
I this this line, the first lines or not?
And this over here.
So this is obvious name.
And this is actually the domain activity.
So it's okay to just save it.
Close our emulator.
Build it again.
Okay.
So now the build is completed.
So let's pull your screen.
Okay, then let's run it to once again.
Get around them later.
Okay, let's earn it.
We can.
All snapshots, sir.
No shock.
So I'm just putting them later.
Okay let me do this says temporarily let me around 30 below ask for apparently so it's not yet up.
Well, I think.
So it's starting.
Okay.
So let's do thing let's first check whether our service is running or not.
And then we will take a look at.
So here you go.
This is our service.
So our service is actually running.
So this is the service name.
Here you can see this is the service name and this is our stub.
Which we created earlier.
So now our services are running and it's up.
And if you take the logcat, you can see that it's a policy issue.
Error, which we had earlier is now banished.
Okay.
So so that was a cucumber demo on how to create a system service in Android.